Excuse me.
我先走了
"Marunouchi North"
（丸之內北站）
Sorry.
抱歉
I'm getting on.
我要搭車
I'll call you.
我再打電話給你 但我不知道你的號碼…
Haruko.
春子前輩
Tomorrow is payday.
明天就要發薪了
Yes. So?
那又怎樣？
It's my first payday, so I'm already excited.
這是我的第一份薪水 我好興奮啊
My parents did so much for me.
也給爸媽添了不少麻煩
So I think I'll send them a gift.
所以我想買些什麼送他們
I wonder what I should get them.
買什麼好呢？
Mori, you care about your parents a lot.
小森你…
You'll face the reality tomorrow.
明天你就會嘗到現實的殘酷了
- What? - The reality of a temp worker.
-咦？ -派遣的現實呢
The reality of a temp worker?
派遣的現實？
I'm so jealous of Satomi.
好羨慕里美
She must be in her wedding dress by now.
她現在一定穿著婚紗…
You're in my way.
擋路
Sorry.
抱歉
I'd like to hear your opinion
前輩，想問你當作參考
on marriage between an employee and a temp worker.
派遣和正職員工結婚 你有什麼看法？
Don't get married on a weekday. It causes inconvenience to others.
婚禮辦在上班時間 拖慢工作進度，很礙事
Totally agreed.
沒錯
That's not what I'm asking.
我不是在問這個…
The venue only had an opening today, and it's a lucky day today.
大安好像只有今天 有空的婚禮場地
So love between a permanent employee and a temp...
那你覺得正職員工 和派遣員工談戀愛…
You're in my way.
你也很擋路
Sorry.
對不起
Ms Omae doesn't seem to like this kind of topic.
大前小姐好像討厭這種話題呢
Any woman past 30 hates this kind of topic.
年過三十的女人都討厭吧
You're in my way!
擋路
Satomi, the bride, graduated from Yamato Junior College
新娘里美以優秀的成績
with outstanding grades.
從大和二專畢業後
She now works as a temp worker for Global Staff Service.
進入國際人力派遣公司 當派遣員工
She's building up her career at various different companies.
在各式各樣的職場累積經驗
- Such as S&amp;F... - A temp?
-並在S&amp;F… -派遣員工？
Masaki.
正樹
You never told me that.
你怎麼沒跟我說？
We approved this marriage
我們可是以為
because we thought she was a proper permanent employee.
她是穩定正派的正職員工 才答應這門婚事的
Are you looking down on her?
你這是看不起我女兒嗎？
Your son, a permanent employee,
先對派遣員工出手的 是你家兒子吧
You're the MC, do something.
東海林先生
It just started.
婚禮才剛開始就搞這齣
You're the one who did...
那是你們的問題
Well...
不好意思
It has been a wonderful reception.
在各位興頭上打擾了
But there's a change in the programme.
現在我們稍微加快流程
The bride will now go change her dress.
新娘該準備換下一套禮服了
So she'll step out for a bit. Thank you for your understanding.
讓她先退場休息一下吧
No!
我不要
I...
我不想再出場了
Satomi...
里美
Let's talk after the reception.
-婚禮結束我們再談談好嗎 -不要，我不要啦
The bride is crying and refusing to come back in.
聽說新娘
What do we do?
怎麼辦？
I can't believe this. The reception will end soon.
饒了我吧 這樣下去整場婚禮就泡湯了
Oh, good. They're here.
太好了，她願意出場了
Huh?
奇怪？
She looks quite plain now.
服裝未免也太過樸素了吧
Yeah, not even a dress?
看起來的確不像禮服
She looks familiar.
不覺得這身影好像在哪看過？
Could it be?
該不會是
That's Omae.
-是大前 -為什麼
Omae.
大前小姐
Turtleneck.
套頭毛衣女
She's coming here.
她走過來了
Is she angry?
她在生氣嗎
She didn't need to come here.
那也沒必要氣到跑來吧
What?
怪了
- Sir. - Yes?
-部長 -怎麼了
Here's the estimate of the social expenses due today.
這是今天要提交的 營業部招待費預算表
Please approve and stamp this.
請您蓋章簽呈
Sorry, but I don't have my stamp with me.
抱歉
Please.
麻煩您了
Sure.
好
Excuse me.
那我告辭了
Thank you.
辛苦了
Oh, no.
糟糕
She's coming this way.
她過來了
- I'm sorry. - Chief Satonaka?
對不起
- Yes? - It's almost 6.
-是 -再一分鐘就六點了
- Okay. - Can I go home now?
-我能直接下班嗎
- Sure. - Please.
可以
Excuse me.
告辭
Proud employees will fall.
正職員工獨大的天下不再
Companies won't survive without temp workers now.
如今沒有一間公司 不依賴派遣社員
For example, Haruko Omae here.
就像這位大前春子
"Impossible" and "overtime" are not in her dictionary.
她的字典裡沒有不可能和加班
She shuts down all troublesome relationships
拋開繁複的人際關係
and disappears after three months when her contract ends.
三個月聘僱期一過
But why did the super temp worker, Haruko Omae,
但超級派遣員工大前春子 究竟為何
decide to be a non-permanent employee?
選擇與正職員工之路背道而馳
That's still a mystery.
沒有人知道
"The Pride Of The Temp"
派遣員的品格
The reception was a disaster.
那場婚禮真是一團亂
"Love and hourly wage"
〝戀愛與時薪〞
So Takahashi didn't tell his parents that he was marrying a temp?
高橋沒先跟爸媽說 對象是派遣員工嗎
Maybe he couldn't.
應該是說不出口吧
His parents are brand-conscious.
他父母對媳婦家世很要求的
He knew that they wouldn't approve of the marriage.
他也知道父母 不會接受派遣員工吧
Wow, this is shocking.
我覺得好受打擊
I had no idea temp workers were seen that way.
原來派遣員工這麼受到歧視
We're just co-workers, no one is superior than others.
在同個職場奮鬥的夥伴 是沒有上下之分的
That's right.
就是說啊，小森
That's a naive way of thinking.
主任，那不過是漂亮話罷了
We live in a stratified society.
這社會可不平等
Employees look at the temp workers who don't get bonuses
-看著沒獎金拿的派遣員工 -正職員工竊喜著有人墊底
and feel better about themselves.
大家都只求安心
You don't want to go there.
別再說這種喪氣話了
I don't get a bonus, either.
我也沒有獎金
Oh, wait.
不過…
What about you, the girl with a 3,000-yen hourly wage?
這位時薪三千圓的大姊 又是如何呢？
Apparently, now she's getting paid 3,500 yen after the tuna incident.
不，聽說鮪魚那件事後 時薪升到三千五百圓了
What?
-竟然 -不平等和歧視根本無關痛癢
Thanks to lazy permanent employees, we temps get to work
因為有不務正業的正職
Any problems?
有什麼不對？
Come on, guys. Work.
開工了
Don't worry about it.
別把她的話放在心上
Was that about me?
是在講我嗎
Good morning.
早安
Did Takahashi manage to leave on his honeymoon?
高橋成功去度蜜月了嗎
Yes, it appears that way.
好像不顧父母反對硬是出發了
That's good to hear.
是嗎，太好了
Omae? Can you come here?
對了，大前你來一下
Yes?
您找我嗎？
About the tuna fileting show...
前陣子鮪魚解體秀的事
The executives heard about it.
傳到公司上層耳裡了
They think it'd be a shame to let you go after three months.
他們說三個月 就放你這種人才走太可惜
I also would like you to continue working with us here.
我也希望你能繼續在這裡工作
As I explained at the beginning,
我在一開始見面時就說了
there will be no extension to my contract.
我不續約
Can you at least give it a thought?
別這麼說，考慮一下吧
At one point,
我們也有考慮
we want to hire you permanently.
讓你轉正職的意思
It's not a bad idea for you, right?
這對你來說也不壞吧？
I decline.
請恕我拒絕
What?
什麼？
I don't want to be a slave and be tied up to a company.
我不想成為被公司束縛的奴隸
Is that everything?
您的事說完了嗎
Sure.
對
Excuse me.
那我失陪了
Slave? She meant us?
意思是我們是奴隸嗎
She called us lazy earlier, too. She says whatever she feels like.
剛才還大放厥詞 說正職不務正業怎樣的
She doesn't understand the situation at all. Am I right?
她都不看場合講話的，對吧？
- Right! - You should go and yell at her.
-就是說啊 -你快去念她一頓啊
Yeah, go for it.
-狠狠教訓她一頓 -快上啊
What a snob.
叫她少囂張
All right.
好
Yes. That's our man.
-上吧 -給她點顏色瞧瞧
Haruko Omae.
大前春子小姐
Yes?
有事嗎
You know...
我說你啊
What?
怎樣？
You know what?
就是…
Just tell me what you want. I'm busy.
我很忙的，有事快說
That's fine if you're busy.
你忙的話就算了
Hey, what's going on? Shoji?
等等，東海林你是怎麼了？
What are you doing?
你在搞什麼東西
She said she's busy.
她都說在忙了我能怎樣
You go back to work now!
你們還不快工作
Everyone is so lazy here.
還真是群不務正業的人
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
The croquette set menu, please.
可樂餅套餐一份
Same for me, too.
我也來一份
Sometimes it's nice to eat at a cheap place like this.
偶爾來這種質樸的店也不錯
If you want to talk to Omae, go ahead.
你有話對大前小姐說就快去
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
Oh, Turtleneck is here.
原來套頭毛衣女在這啊
Don't pretend to act cool.
你就別裝傻了
What?
-什麼？ -謝謝惠顧
Sorry.
先說聲抱歉
But I saw it.
我不小心看到了
Saw what?
看到什麼？
What do you mean, "what"?
你還問
You know...
就是
You and Omae at the bus stop.
你在公車站吻了大前…
I don't know what happened.
我不知道怎麼回事
She did the tuna fileting show, which really saved me.
她為了幫我搞了場鮪魚解體秀
So I went to thank her.
我想跟她道謝
Then...
然後就
it was like I was drawn to her.
有種整個人要陷進去的感覺
Before I knew it,
回過神來
I was doing that.
就變成那樣了
I see.
原來如此
What?
話說…
Is that sexual harassment?
這樣算性騷擾嗎
She's leaving.
她要走掉了
Oh, hey.
咦？
You're here.
還真巧
Omae.
在這遇到你
- See you later. - Hey.
我先走了
I'm sorry.
抱歉，那個…
I wanted to call you, but I don't have your number.
我想打給你但不知道你的號碼
Wait.
等一下
Could it be...
你是不是
that you're angry at me?
在對之前的事生氣？
Don't worry about it.
你不必放在心上
Okay, good.
這樣啊
That's good to know.
太好了，那就好
I'll give you my number.
那我給你我的電話號碼
It's hard to talk at work,
在公司很難說上話
so call me.
打電話給我吧
Please don't worry about it, really.
真的，請不必放在心上
Thank you.
謝謝惠顧
I don't get it at all.
好難懂啊，真是的
You know the type of girls that I've dated, right?
小賢，你知道 我交過的女友類型吧？
Elegant girls who made me look good.
優雅又很給男人面子
Girls who had nice smiles.
笑起來很可愛
She's the complete opposite.
那女人完全相反
That's right.
是啊
It's something new. I'll make her mine.
難得有機會 我是不是該把她一下？
Shoji.
東海林先生
Is that how you really feel?
你這樣也太輕浮了吧
Why are you mad?
為什麼你要生氣？
Are you into her, too?
難道說你也對她有意思？
No, I'm not.
才不是
Sixty days left...
還有六十天啊…
I wonder how much money I got for my first salary.
薪水有多少呢？
"Wage, Haken Life, 103,200"
（十萬零三千二百圓）
No way.
騙人的吧
You received your first salary?
你領到第一份薪水了？
Congrats.
恭喜
I'm not happy.
沒什麼好恭喜的
What should I do?
怎麼辦
That usually happens in the first month.
第一個月都會受到打擊的
We had many holidays in January, too.
一月的假日也比較多
You knew that temps get paid hourly, right?
你應該知道 派遣員工都是算時薪的吧
Yes, but after rent and utilities,
可是付了房租和水電費
I won't make it to the next payday.
就不夠用到下個月了
What should I do?
怎麼辦？
Samples will arrive at 4.
四點的時候樣品會送到
- Check it. - Okay.
-你再去確認一下 -是
Here's your tea.
請用茶
The Russian company, Michka, will be here tomorrow at three.
部長，俄國的謬修卡公司 明天三點會來訪
Finally.
是嗎，終於走到這步了
Omae.
大前小姐
Can you be my secretary tomorrow?
明天能請你當我的助手嗎
It's very important.
這場會議很重要
Please.
我也拜託你了
Understood.
我知道了
I'll be in charge of the meeting.
商談就讓我來
You just need to sit there.
雖說你只要輔助我就好
Look through this.
還是姑且看看資料吧
Do you need an interpreter?
需要幫你翻譯嗎
No need.
不用 我在莫斯科分公司待過兩年
I see.
這樣啊
Haruko.
春子前輩
I have a favour to ask.
-我有事想拜託你 -我拒絕
I haven't said anything.
我什麼都還沒說
You don't have to say it.
不用聽也知道
Please.
拜託了
Lend me some money.
請借我錢
I knew it.
果然
I promised my landlord that I'll pay after payday.
我跟房東講好
Then keep that promise.
請遵守約定
But if I paid my rent, I won't have money to live.
可是我付了房租 生活費就不夠了
I'll really go broke.
這次真的要破產了
Then go broke.
那你就破產吧
How is it going?
後來怎麼樣？
How are Omae and Mori from our agency?
我們的大前、森和近 有沒有搞砸什麼
Very good.
沒有…
They're doing a great job.
他們表現都很好
Especially Omae.
特別是大前小姐，非常優秀
Glad to hear that.
那太好了
About Omae...
說到那個大前
Does she speak Russian?
她會說俄語嗎
One moment, please.
稍等一下
She doesn't have certificates on Russian.
她好像還沒拿到俄語證書
Okay.
是喔
That's fine.
那很好
What?
什麼？
Well...
因為
she tends to get bossy in fields she's good at.
如果她俄語很強 就沒有我表現的餘地了
Not making us look good.
-身為正職很沒面子 -真不好意思
Please.
一木先生，請用
She hasn't called me.
她都不打來…
What?
什麼？
Can you give me her number?
能給我大前的電話號碼嗎
I want to talk to her about work.
我想跟她討論開會的事
Well...
不…
Sorry, but I can't.
這點請饒了我吧
It's personal information.
不能洩漏派遣人員的個資
You can call me if it's urgent.
有緊急的事請透過我聯絡
Should I call her?
要現在打嗎
Don't worry about it.
不用了
How old is she?
話說她幾歲？
I can't tell you.
請別這樣
- Please. - Come on.
-有什麼關係 -不行…
You know, the harder you try to hide it,
你愈是拼命藏
the more I want to know.
就愈讓人好奇呢
Don't go too deep into this.
請別再深入追究了
The most common problem with temps is the pay.
派遣人員最常出的問題 是時薪談不攏
And the second one
再來就是…
is erotic dramas with employees.
和正職傳出戀愛八卦
Are you all right, Hitotsugi?
一木先生沒事吧？
[Foreign language]
（俄語）
You're serious about this.
你很用功嘛
Oh, yeah?
對啊
I haven't spoken Russian in three years.
畢竟我有三年沒用俄語了
You need to impress Omae.
得讓大前小姐 看看你帥氣的一面呢
Oh, come on.
說什麼蠢話
It's Azuma.
是東啊…
Hello?
你好
What's up?
怎麼了
Do it tomorrow.
這種事明天再講就好了
I'll hang up now.
我要掛掉了
Seriously?
真是夠了
Shoji?
東海林先生
Aren't you actually...
你其實
jealous of her?
很羨慕大前小姐吧
What? Why?
為什麼這麼說？
When you see her,
不覺得看著她
it makes me question if everything that I built until now
就覺得我們進公司後 累積起來的一切
meant anything.
到底算什麼嗎
Yeah.
的確
It feels like she's destroying everything I've built.
自我認同好像要分崩離析一般
You're fine.
沒問題的
Competent girls like Omae
大前小姐這種工作女強人
will surely find competent guys like you attractive.
一定會喜歡上
You're cheering me up?
你這是在鼓勵我嗎
If you're serious,
如果你對她是認真的 我會支持你
Good luck with the negotiation tomorrow.
明天的會議
Thanks.
好
Shoji.
東海林先生 這是炸蝦試吃和冷凍樣品
Keep them in the freezer and serve them in the meeting.
把樣品冰好 進會議室前再拿出來
- Sure. - Shoji.
東海林先生
Yes?
在
This is a research on the Philippines.
菲律賓漁場的調查資料 你要用嗎
The data is outdated.
這數據也太舊了吧
I won't need it.
先不用，謝謝
Put these in a locker.
-森，把這些放進資料櫃 -好的
What are you doing?
-對不起 -你在幹嘛？
- I'm sorry. - The contract.
-合約…
Find the contract.
合約在哪
Here it is.
找到了
- I'm sorry. - Careful.
-對不起 -小心點啊
- Clean this up.
-快收拾
It's time.
好，時間到了
- Let's go meet them. - All right.
-去迎接客人吧 -好
- Omae, too. Let's go. - Sure.
-大前小姐也來
Let's go.
走吧
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
It's fine.
沒關係
It's mixed up.
都混在一起了
I'm sorry.
怎麼辦…
Welcome, Tatiana.
塔季揚娜小姐，歡迎
[Foreign language]
（俄語）
Thank you all.
有勞各位出來迎接
Please follow us.
請進
[Foreign language]
（俄語）
We won't use these for a while
這些資料應該好一陣子用不到
so put them in the shared locker.
就先放進共用資料櫃吧
Understood.
好的
- Here's the key. - Okay.
-用這支鑰匙 -好
- Are you okay? - Yes.
-還好嗎 -沒問題
Please place them here.
就放進來這裡吧
"Sales Division 2"
（販賣二課）
Please also serve tea in the meeting room.
再麻煩你端茶進會議室
Sure.
好的
Omae is busy today.
大前小姐今天應該會很忙
- Sure. - Thank you.
-好的 -麻煩了
All right.
好
"Marketing, Sales Division 1, Sales Division 2"
（行銷課，販賣一課 販賣二課）
Shrimps from the Philippines are that expensive?
菲律賓的冷凍蝦這麼貴嗎
[Foreign language]
塔季揚娜小姐
These are the highest grade shrimps.
這是最高級的蝦子
You guys are the same as other companies.
這價格跟其他公司沒有兩樣
[Foreign language]
不…
They're saying that our prices are very high.
她說我們的報價很貴
This might get a bit tricky.
這樁生意不好談呢
You only get 1,200 yen?
你時薪只有一千二百圓啊？
Why don't you sign up to my agency?
要不要來登錄 我這間派遣公司？
They might have higher paying jobs.
說不定能介紹給你 時薪更高的工作
Can I do that?
可以這樣嗎
Everyone does that.
大家都這麼做
- Right? - Yeah.
-對吧 -是啊
Really?
這樣啊
I'm signed up with three agencies.
我也同時登錄了三間
Are you really?
真的嗎
To the USA and Europe, we sell them
歐美企業的價格
If you want to have business with Russians,
要賣來俄國的話
you need to also consider the domestic selling prices there.
必須把俄國國內的
It's fine.
-東海林 -沒問題
Understood, but--
我知道，但…
We can't accept it!
我們不能接受
[Foreign language]
我們何必…
Do you think we'll buy things that won't sell in Russia?
要買在俄國賣不出去的東西？
"Staff resourcing company"
（立刻登錄）
It's taking a long time.
他們談好久
Mori?
-森 -是
Can you serve them coffee again?
你可以再端一次咖啡進去嗎
- Sure. - See how it's going.
-好的 -順便看看談得如何
Okay.
好的
That's not possible...
貴公司的要求太…
The purchase price must be a lot cheaper.
採購價格應該更便宜才對
Our price includes human labour and transportation.
還得算上人事費用和運輸費
You know, you're not the only companies out here.
還有很多其他公司可以選
No need for tea.
不用上茶了
What?
-什麼？ -再一分鐘就結束了
Our product is ranked higher.
我們的品質可不一般
Please accept this price.
請接受這個價格吧
This is unacceptable.
跟你根本說不通
You Japanese are so cheap, you only think about making money.
日本人都貪財又吝嗇
[Foreign language]
（俄語）
What?
怎麼回事？
What's going on?
到底怎麼了
It's a deal.
剛才談成功了
Really?
真的？
At our price.
她同意按我們的報價買
That's great.
同意了
Thank you.
請多指教
Sir.
部長
It's 6, so I'll leave now.
六點了，我下班了
My mother used her savings and paid my rent.
媽媽用私房錢匯給房東 幫我繳了房租
I was going to send them a gift, but they're still helping me out.
別說買禮物送他們 反而又給他們添麻煩了
Are you only working with Haken Life?
春子前輩只有 在派遣生活登錄嗎
I have one body, so one is enough.
身體只有一個 登錄一間就夠了
Apparently they pay less than other agencies.
那邊的時薪好像 比其他派遣公司都要低
You're complaining like a real temp worker now.
你當派遣學到的 只有發牢騷比別人強呢
You're lucky because you're so skilled and have a high rate.
那是因為前輩你會的東西多 時薪也優渥，才會不在乎
But getting certified costs money.
可是考證照很花錢
I don't have that kind of money.
我現在也沒有多餘的精力去考
I won't get a raise anytime soon, either.
時薪看起來也沒有會漲的跡象
A poor temp worker can't get out of being poor.
沒錢的派遣員工根本 會一直窮下去吧？
What?
奇怪？
Anything you want to say?
怎麼了？
You're pretty but you have terrible luck.
你啊
What?
什麼？
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
Mori?
森？
Hi there.
你們好
Wow, incredible.
好厲害
This is no good...
小賢，我不行了
I'm starting to feel dizzy.
我開始暈了
Hey.
跟你說
There's a guy who's my type.
那個很對我胃口的男人來了
A guy with curly hair.
捲捲頭
I'll go upstairs now.
媽媽，那我先走了
Haruko, Chief Satonaka is asking for you.
前輩，里中主任他們想找你
I'm finished for the day.
我今天已經下班了
It seems quite important.
他們要講的事好像很重要
Omae.
大前小姐
Please sit.
請坐
It's outside of my work hours.
現在非上班時段
What do you want?
請問有何貴幹？
Well, we wanted to thank you for today.
那個，今天開會的事 我想跟你道謝
I had no idea you speak perfect Russian.
你俄語講得很好呢 嚇了我一大跳
Hitotsugi said that you didn't have any Russian certificates.
一木先生的資料裡 沒有寫你會俄語
I have so many certificates that I couldn't list them all.
我會的技能太多了寫不下 所以我省略沒寫
Is that so?
原來如此
I did it as a part of my job.
況且那只是工作的一部分
There's no need for you to come here
沒有特地跑來這
Well...
這…
You're right.
你說的是
Omae...
大前小姐
Shoji wanted to personally thank you for it.
東海林先生他是 個人想跟你道謝而來的
Even outside the office,
出了公司
we can still interact as people.
-多少和人來往也不壞 -我挑明說了
it's waste of time.
這是浪費時間
Really?
怎麼會
Shoji was waiting for you to call him.
東海林先生…
He wanted to see you.
他是想見你才會特地來的
Ken.
小賢
Instead of here,
在這講話不方便
can we talk outside?
能跟我出去一下嗎
I wanted to talk to you.
我一直想跟你談談
You always go home quickly
但你總是逃也似地
like you're running away.
很快就下班了
Why didn't you...
怎麼也不打電話
It's cold, so I'll skip some parts
天氣很冷
to the conclusion.
直接問你了
Do you like me?
你喜歡我嗎
Or no?
還是討厭我？
It's not about liking you or not liking you.
不是喜歡或討厭的問題
What?
什麼？
Let's ask a temp out because they'll quit soon.
派遣員工待不長 約起來沒壓力
If it gets complicated, dump them.
得手後一出問題就立刻切割
I've seen many employees like that.
這種正職員工我看得可多了
You think I'm like that?
-你覺得我也是這種人？ -沒錯
Why are you like that?
你為什麼老是這樣？
Why are you so depressing?
總是說些孤單的話
You never smile at work.
在公司也完全不笑
But that actually makes me more interested.
但這樣反而更讓我在意
You know.
你應該要…
Open up to us more.
更敞開心胸
You told me that I had no social skills.
你自己也說了 我的社交能力是零
Yes, I did. It's true.
我是說了，因為是事實
So work on that.
-你就想辦法改 -對派遣人員講這些只是徒然
- Why? - Companies hire us temporarily
-為什麼 -公司想要暫時性勞力
and buy our labour in small quantities.
才會短期雇用我們派遣員工
Being nice to people and smiling are for permanent employees.
溫柔相待、笑顏以對
Are you serious?
你真這麼想？
Yes.
對
What the heck?
莫名其妙
You're so twisted.
你的思想有夠扭曲
Who are you to say? You're anti-temp.
-你這反派遣人士憑什麼說我 -沒錯
But you're good.
但我肯定你的表現
You're a super temp.
我覺得你很優秀
I want to do good work with you.
我想跟你一起在職場上努力
Working together with someone
一起工作
is the same as living with someone.
不就意味著一起活下去嗎
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼夢話？
I'll be gone in two months.
我這份工作做兩個月就要走了
So what?
那又如何？
My feelings might get stronger in two months.
說不定兩個月後我會更喜歡你
It's so cold.
好冷…
They already emailed me.
已經寄資訊來了
"New job openings"
（員工資源公司職缺）
It's a job as a receptionist.
櫃台的工作嗎
"Receptionist job"
（櫃台接待人員）
It pays 1,800 yen per hour?
時薪一千八百圓？
What should I do?
怎麼辦…
"1,800 yen per hour"
（時薪一千八百圓）
Hi, is this Kaori? It's Mori.
你好，是小香嗎？
I was introduced to a job with a great pay.
新公司馬上就介紹 時薪優渥的工作給我了
But the consultation is tomorrow.
可是面試訂在明天
I have to go to work, so what should I do?
還得去上班，該怎麼辦才好？
You can come up with an excuse and take a day off.
找個藉口請假不就好了
Everyone does that.
大家都這樣做
Seriously?
真的嗎
1,800 yen per hour, huh...
時薪一千八百圓嗎
All right.
好
Hello?
你好
Everything okay, Mori?
森，怎麼這麼晚打來？
Actually, my mum back home suddenly fell ill.
其實我媽突然生病倒下了
Okay.
是
I want to go back to Gunma tomorrow.
所以我明天得回去群馬一趟
Can I have a day off?
可以幫我請假嗎
It's true. Please believe me.
是真的，請相信我
I understand.
我明白的
I've worked with many people.
畢竟我也閱人無數
I know you would never skip work.
我知道你不是那種會偷懶的人
You must be worried, then.
你很擔心媽媽吧
I'll call Chief Satonaka for you.
我會幫你跟里中主任講
Sickness of family.
家人突然生病啊
That was the sixth one I had today.
你是今天第六個人了
This isn't good.
不妙
So Mori will be taking a day off today.
基於我剛才說的原因 今天森要請假
Should I send someone?
要安排其他人過去嗎
No, it's okay.
沒關係的
Omae is here.
有大前小姐在
Okay, thank you.
好的，謝謝你
- Bye. - You're good.
-再見 -你很會按耶
Omae.
-真的嗎 -大前小姐
Mori's mother fell ill.
聽說森的媽媽突然生病了
Really?
什麼？
Fell sick, huh?
突然生病是嗎
So please cover Mori's tasks today.
所以森的工作 今天就麻煩你處理了
Thank you.
-謝啦 -好
Understood.
我知道了
That's Mori's seat.
你坐到森的位置了
What am I doing?
我怎麼會犯這種錯
Sir, Chief Shoji is out sick today.
部長，東海林主任重感冒 今天來不了
Okay.
了解
They have lots of sick days.
正職真好，有很多有薪假
Sales Division.
您好，這裡是營業部
Hello?
你好？
Omae?
大前小姐
It's upside down.
筆拿反了
What am I doing?
我怎麼會犯這種錯
Please wait just a second.
請您稍等一下
Director, it's Tatiana from Michka.
部長，是謬修卡公司的 塔季揚娜小姐
She keeps saying "Shoji, please."
吵著要找東海林，而且…
She doesn't speak English or Japanese.
-英語和日語都不通，怎麼辦 -大前
Please.
麻煩你接電話
Hey!
怎麼了？
Hello?
（俄語）
What?
什麼？
She has to go back to Russia right away,
他們突然趕著要回國
so they want to sign the contract by 3:00 this afternoon.
今天三點前要跟他們簽約
They'd like to get the required documents.
還叫我們備齊需要的文件
That's not nice.
-根本在故意找麻煩 -事情大條了，借過…
Contract!
合約…
- You have everything? - Wait.
-文件備齊了嗎 -請稍等
We're missing the invoice.
糟糕了，少了業務發票
Call Shoji now.
快打給東海林
His phone is turned off.
不行，他手機沒開
Why is the invoice missing?
怎麼會只少了業務發票
Look for it.
快找
Oh, wait.
啊
What is it, Satonaka?
里中，怎麼了？
Maybe, back then...
該不會是那時
- I'm sorry. - What are you doing?
-對不起 -小心點啊
Please.
就放進來這裡吧
It might be with old documents.
可能和舊資料混在一起了
Mori has the key.
鑰匙放在森那裡
What?
什麼？
It's at her desk.
去森的桌子找找
We have no time.
沒時間了
Where is it?
在哪裡
It's not here.
-沒有… -部長，找不到
Maybe she took it home.
-該不會帶回家了 -她又搞這種飛機？
Look for the spare.
-去找備用鑰匙 -備用鑰匙…
Hello?
你好
Is this Mori's residence?
請問府上是森美雪的老家嗎 我是派遣生活的一木
Is Miyuki there?
請問她在嗎
There's an emergency at the company she works for.
其實她做派遣的公司 有要緊的事
I'm sorry to bother you when her mother is ill.
在伯母生重病時打擾 真的很不好意思
You're her mother?
您就是伯母本人嗎
You're fine?
健康得不得了
All right, I see.
我知道了
I wonder how Mori's consultation is going.
不知道森的面試順不順利
It pays 1,800 yen per hour.
時薪一千八百圓嗎
Receptionists are that well paid?
坐櫃台這麼賺啊？
So that's what this is about.
果然是這麼回事
Hi, Omae.
大前小姐…
Where's the company that pays 1,800 yen?
時薪一千八的那間公司在哪？
Tell me!
快說
I'll borrow this.
借我騎一下
Hey!
等等
Wait!
喂
My name is Miyuki Mori. Nice to meet you.
我是森美雪，我來面試了
- Okay, let's go. - Yes.
那我們走吧
Miyuki Mori there.
森美雪，給我站住
Wait.
不准走
Haruko?
春子前輩？
I have a consultation now.
我接下來要面試
Please don't stop me.
請讓我去…
The key.
鑰匙
The key?
鑰匙？
You have the key of the locker, right?
你拿著資料櫃的鑰匙吧？
Hand it to me.
快給我
Now!
快點
Okay.
好的
Well...
我找找
Here it is!
找到了
Haruko?
前輩
You're burning up.
前輩你燒得好嚴重
You're running a high fever!
都發燒了，你還好嗎
Haruko!
前輩
Omae.
大前小姐
Where have you been?
你去哪了？
Out of my way.
請讓開
It's the key.
鑰匙來了
It opened.
開了
This is it.
是這張吧？
Yes, the invoice!
對，就是這張業務發票
All the documents are here now.
這樣文件就備齊了
Yes!
找到了
Yes! We did it!
太好了
They're here.
趕得上簽約了
This way, please.
請進
Welcome.
歡迎
Didn't you pass my car?
你剛才是不是超我車？
Yes. So?
那又如何？
Hey, Mum?
媽媽
Thank you for the money.
謝謝你匯錢過來
Hello?
我說美雪
What are you doing?
你到底在那邊做什麼？
What?
做什麼…
I'm just working.
當然是上班啊
Earlier, I got a phone call from your agency.
剛才派遣公司的一木先生
I'm sorry for making up that lie, Mum.
媽，對不起
But everyone does it.
可是這種事大家都在做
Miyuki.
美雪
Are you healthy?
你身體還好嗎
Are you eating well?
有沒有好好吃飯？
I'm worried about you.
爸爸也很擔心你
If it's too hard for you, you can always come home.
覺得難受的話
Omae.
大前小姐
Nice work today as always.
今天真的辛苦你了
Nice work.
主任也辛苦了
Mori.
森
Is your mother okay?
你媽媽還好嗎
I'm sorry.
對不起
That was...
那是…
actually a lie.
騙人的
What?
什麼？
I'm sorry.
對不起
Haruko?
前輩
You had a high fever. Are you okay now?
你燒得那麼厲害，要不要緊？
Omae.
大前小姐
- Haruko. - Omae.
-前輩 -大前小姐
Ms Haruko, are you okay?
前輩，你還好嗎
Omae!
-前輩 -大前小姐
She's such a troublesome girl.
這孩子真讓人操心
She went to work with a 39-degree fever.
燒到三十九度竟然還去上班
No problem.
不…
If Omae didn't come to work,
要是今天沒有大前小姐
it would've been a disaster.
才真的麻煩大了
It's my fault.
都是我的錯
I made her work so hard.
讓前輩這麼勉強自己
What am I doing?
我到底在幹嘛
Miyuki.
美雪
Don't be so hard on yourself.
你沒必要這麼焦急
Haruko, too,
春子她啊
started with a cashier's job that only paid 600 yen an hour.
一開始也是從 時薪六百圓的收銀員做起的
What?
什麼？
What do you think she did to get to this point?
你想她怎麼能變成 這麼厲害的派遣人員？
Never in her life,
她從來不會
she has broken promises.
做到一半就違約跑了
No matter how hard her job was,
不管被派到多辛苦的公司
she never ran away from it during the three months contract.
三個月的雇用期間 絕不逃避做到底
She often said,
她常說
"Once you run away,
一旦逃了
you will always run away from your problems."
一生都得逃個不停
"Curly Hair's phone number"
（捲捲頭手機號碼）
Working together is the same thing as living together.
一起工作
My feelings might get stronger in two months.
說不定兩個月後我會更喜歡你
Haruko.
春子前輩
Are you feeling better?
感冒好了嗎
You need to get better on weekends, or you'll lose people's trust.
感冒就該在週末治好 休息一天也會影響到評價
Understood.
知道了
And your 1,800-yen receptionist's job?
你不是要去做 時薪一千八的櫃台嗎
I didn't take it.
我放棄了
They refused you?
在面試被刷掉了吧？
That's not true.
才不是
It was stupid of me to do that because I thought everyone did it.
跟著大家隨波逐流的我 真是太蠢了
Temps are looked down upon because they do things like that.
正因為大家都這麼做 派遣人員才會被看扁對吧
I'll work hard for 1,200 yen.
時薪一千二我也要努力
My goal is a contract renewal in two months.
目標是兩個月後能續約
You look like you're in bad shape.
東海林先生 你感冒好像很不舒服
Are you all right?
還好嗎
I caught something terrible.
感覺這次感冒特別嚴重
Good morning.
早安
- Morning. - Good morning.
-早 -早安
Good morning.
早安
Omae.
大前小姐
While I was out sick,
聽說在我病倒時
I heard that you managed to get the contract signed.
你幫我處理了簽約的事
It was Director Kirishima who got the contract signed. So?
合約是桐島部長簽的 有什麼問題嗎
Well...
沒什麼…
Let me treat you to dinner tonight.
我想趁今晚道謝
The first meal we'll share together.
就當紀念我倆初次吃飯深談
How about puffer fish?
要不要跟我去吃河豚？
Puffer fish?
河豚
You hate it?
你不喜歡？
I love it to death.
喜歡得要命
That's good.
太好了
- So... - I don't want to eat it with you.
-那… -但我不想跟你一起吃
What?
什麼？
Why?
-為什麼？ -時薪調到三千萬也不跟你吃
Wait a minute.
等，等一下
Just so you know...
我們好歹…
that thing happened between us,
也做了那種事
and you said you weren't angry.
你也說你沒有生氣
If there's a fly, flying around
只不過是在周圍轉的蒼蠅
and it happens to land on your lips,
偶然停在我的嘴唇上罷了
would anyone be angry with the fly?
哪有人類會對蒼蠅動怒？
- A fly? - Yes.
-蒼蠅？ -對
A fly.
就是蒼蠅
Wait!
給我站住
If I was a fly,
我是蒼蠅的話
you'd be a telephone pole.
你就是電線桿
I just happened to
我也不過是…
bump into a telephone pole.
偶然撞上電線杆罷了
Calm down, Shoji.
-東海林先生，冷靜 -別攔我，小賢
She said I was a fly!
她竟然說我是蒼蠅
Nobody likes you.
誰會對你這種…
You, Turtleneck!
對你這個套頭毛衣女
Telephone pole!
對一根電線桿有意思啊
- Are you all right? - Of course not!
-沒事吧？ -怎麼可能沒事
Fever's going up.
燒得更厲害了
That idiot.
看什麼熱鬧，混蛋
Turtleneck is beating up Ogasawara!
套頭毛衣女 快要勒死小笠原先生了
His contract won't be renewed.
-小笠原先生沒辦法續約了 -真的嗎
A temp can't tell me to fire him.
-幹嘛讓派遣員工害自己被炒 -是人事部的決定
Taking care of a lost old man isn't included in my contract.
我的合約裡可沒有寫 要看顧走失老人
Turtleneck!
套頭毛衣女